Mihir Deshpande

DevOps Consultant

+91-7447475011

™ mihirvijdeshpande@gmail.com

github.com/mihirvijdeshpande

Work Experience

DevOps SME

May 2021 - Present

Accenture | Bengaluru

- Consulting and **Designing Processes** for CICD Tools
- Managed CI CD Tool chain for **16+ Applications end-to-end.**
- Managed OpenShift clusters running Spring Boot API Microservices
- Developed and maintained **Branching and Deployment Strategy** for the team
- **Automated** Repeatitive Tasks using **Bash** and **Python** scripting, saving 35+ hours for the team each month
- Improved Deployment Velocity by almost 300% with the help of enhanced processes and workflows.
- **Enabling Dev** team to understand CICD Workflows, Infrastructure and Platforms.
- **Mentoring Young Talent** in learning Industry Best Practices as well as tools like Terraform, Jenkins, AWS

Sr. Associate Consultant - DevOps

Dec 2018 - May 2021

Infosys I Pune

- Automating Repetitive tasks using Python and Shell scripting
- Working on **Ansible Tower, Terrafrom** to automate infrastructure configuration and orchestration.
- Research and Consultation on tools used in **DevOps Pipelines**.
- Worked on CI / CD Tool chain using Github, Jenkins, SonarQube
- Worked on **Compliance Management** tools such as Cloud Custodian, terraform-Kitchen / terratest
- Troubleshooting Incidents, Providing Root Cause Analysis and Delivering Robust Solutions

Software Engineer - Cloud & DevOps

July 2016 - Dec 2018

Zensar I Pune

- Presales RFP on AWS, Ansible, Puppet and Terraform
- Developing and maintaining CICD Pipeline using Github / GitLab,
 Jenkins, SonarQube, Artifactory, Jira
- Manged on-prem physical hardware Cisco UCS, Blade servers.
- Worked on installing and maintaining VMWare ESXi, vCentre and vSphere on physical UCS boxes
- Managed Presales platforms using Linux systems
- Using **Docker** and **K8s** for enabling **microservice** architecture.
- End-to-end **self-healing** pipeline integration and automation using event-rule-action based intelligence.

About Me

I am a DevOps Consultant with proven experience in designing, implementing and automating processes for high-availability systems.

I bring a unique set of skills that help reduce mean-time-to-market for new features and bring down mean-timeto-resolution for defects / bugs.

Education

Bachelor of Engg. (CS) University of Pune

2012 - 2016

Skills

CICD Pipelines Jenkins AWS

SonarQube Artifactory Maven

Python Ansible Terraform

Docker Kubernetes laaC

Automation REST YAML Linux

OpenShift Agile TeamCity

DevOps Java Shell

Hobbies

In my free time I like to volunteer for various **social causes.** I have been a part of **Rotaract** (Rotary for young adults) for around 6 years.

I also volunteer at a Pune based **Theatre** Company, **Aakar Pun**e since the last 5 years. I like to write, act, direct and work on Music Tech.